<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Econosophist</title>
    <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Econosophist</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:48:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Rational Mysticism - Wittgenstein&#39;s Tractatus Logico Philosophicus - Part I</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/tlp1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 10:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/tlp1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One does not hear the words &lt;em&gt;rationality/logic&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;mysticism/spirituality&lt;/em&gt; together but in negation of each other, let alone as a single clause. Is it as contradictory as to say - &lt;em&gt;the fat anorexic&lt;/em&gt;? Well, no. It turns out that mysticism is compatible with rational thought, but in a way that the &lt;em&gt;eyes perceive all except themselves&lt;/em&gt;, or the &lt;em&gt;teeth that bite themselves&lt;/em&gt; - in short, &lt;strong&gt;as the limiting point of a singularity&lt;/strong&gt; which can only be intuited, and not known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein&amp;rsquo;s 75 page work, The &lt;em&gt;Tractatus Logico Philosophicus&lt;/em&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;TLP&lt;/strong&gt; now onward) tackles the fundamental concerns of philosophy, ranging from our perception of reality to ethical questions; from logic and language to mathematics and the mystical - &lt;em&gt;all in a nested framework of seven propositions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein&amp;rsquo;s TLP is an enigmatic work. &lt;em&gt;It is a book which is self aware&lt;/em&gt;, and contains within it layers of meaning, depending on the intention of the reader - the logician can benefit from it as much as a priest, and thus - &lt;em&gt;it serves as a genuine work of philosophy, in its actual scope&lt;/em&gt; - which is simply the result of humanity&amp;rsquo;s self consciousness and the questions it raises - &lt;em&gt;God becomes as much as a relevant concept as logic or ethics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the TLP was simultaneously an emblem for the logical positivists - who argued that &lt;em&gt;all thoughts beyond the fundamental natural sciences are meaningless&lt;/em&gt; to thinkers such as Alan Watts and even Osho, for whom it represented the most lucid and &lt;em&gt;straightforward approach to the doors of enlightenment&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I see the TLP is as &lt;strong&gt;a Zen koan&lt;/strong&gt;( &lt;em&gt;A zen koan is a tool used by Zen masters where the student must solve a riddle which is senseless, so that in solving it, one reaches &lt;strong&gt;Kensho&lt;/strong&gt; - the sudden realization or simply enlightenment&lt;/em&gt;).  At its deepest -  the &lt;strong&gt;TLP is one large koan&lt;/strong&gt;, that is, &lt;strong&gt;it is self-contradictory by design&lt;/strong&gt;, and is &lt;strong&gt;edifying exactly in its self aware contradiction&lt;/strong&gt; - As Wittgenstein cautions us in the penultimate proposition of TLP:-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My propositions are elucidatory in this way: he who understandsme finally recognizes them as senseless, when he has climbed out through them, on them, over them. (H&lt;strong&gt;e must so to speak throwaway the ladder, after he has climbed up on it.&lt;/strong&gt;)He must surmount these propositions; then he sees the world rightly. - 6.54&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who really devote their time and minds to this small but densely cryptic book, they would realize eventually that the seventh proposition, the conclusion of the work serves as a direct contradiction to the first proposition, rendering the whole of TLP as senseless, but from a lower equilibrium of senselessness to a higher one - just as there is the same musical note octaves apart - rendering them the same but not really the same either.[[1]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The World is All that is the Case&lt;/strong&gt; - Prop. 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whereof one cannot speak, thereof one must be silent.&lt;/strong&gt; - Prop. 7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire goal of the TLP is to go through the locus of propositions, and realize that one is not traversing a linear path, but an &lt;em&gt;ouroboros&lt;/em&gt;( a serpent which eats its own tail). The next section delves into my interpretation of the TLP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://digitalpress.fra1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/cwbc7ad/2020/08/tumblr_n77x8s8sZT1twprrlo1_1280.jpg&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Ouroboros&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tlp---analysis&#34;&gt;TLP - Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;preliminaries&#34;&gt;Preliminaries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein starts the TLP as a classic work of metaphysics and ontology - (Of questions relating to reality and existence) through the instruments of logic and language, to disprove their existence as fields of study by its own methodology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The strategy is thus&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;em&gt;There is a &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eality and a reality where&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​														$$reality=f(Reality)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make sense of &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eality(and consequently - reality) we need a unit of measurement, a sort of currency of making reality explicit. Indeed, we all use a unit of ontology without ever questioning the fact that one can perceive Reality using various &lt;em&gt;axes&lt;/em&gt; of cognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manifold world outside human cognition is not dealt with, and is granted the label of &lt;em&gt;substance&lt;/em&gt; - take it as atom, energy, or whatever you want. It is human cognition that cognizes &lt;em&gt;substance&lt;/em&gt; in ontological units - the default unit being objects.[[2]] That is, the World is made up of objects. Thus this is the metaphysical point of departure in Modern Metaphysics, ever since Immanuel Kant dismissed the &lt;em&gt;object outside human cognition as fundamentally unknowable&lt;/em&gt; because our &lt;strong&gt;mind cognizes the manifold as objects in space, time and causal relations, which are not distinct absolute realities, rather the forms of intuition, or more accurately, the conditions which make sense objects intuitable in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein here introduces a radical concept. While after Kant, there arose alternatives to &lt;em&gt;object-oriented-ontology&lt;/em&gt;, such as &lt;em&gt;Event-ontology&lt;/em&gt;(events as the unit of reality) or &lt;em&gt;Process-Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt;(Processes as unit of reality), Wittgenstein incorporated two units of ontology &lt;strong&gt;coexisting simultaneously but independently of each other&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;think quantum theory where light is both a particle and a wave&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These two fundamental units of Reality(once removed from the manifold) are composed of Facts and Objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can see &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eality in terms of &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;acts (I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what they are in detail, but a close analogy for now are &lt;em&gt;events&lt;/em&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt; Objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reality(not to be confused with &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eality) is a function of &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eality and thus &lt;em&gt;twice removed from the manifold&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;reality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is the structure/model of Reality (which is our raw data) and  &lt;em&gt;contains its ontological units as functions of Facts and Objects, as &lt;strong&gt;Propositions&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Names&lt;/strong&gt; respectively&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one can guess, what Wittgenstein is getting to is that &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eality is mirrored/modelled as reality through language.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is to say - &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language mirrors Reality&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; - the consequence of which is that if we can analyze language through its &lt;em&gt;syntax/grammar&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;semantics/meaning&lt;/em&gt;, we can analyze &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eality. To Summarize,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$Names = f(Objects)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$Propositions = f(Facts)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$Language = f(Reality)$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here things become interesting - &lt;code&gt;so I suggest that absorb the basics and pre-requisites now and only proceed when you are comfortable with what has been written up till now.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-analysis&#34;&gt;Core Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein is serious when he proclaims the independence of Facts and Objects. The independence stems from the following reasoning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objects are named. Facts are asserted. Therefore one &lt;strong&gt;cannot assert an object and cannot name Facts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facts are composite units made up of individual atomic units which are indivisible - Wittgenstein calls these units as the &lt;em&gt;atomic fact&lt;/em&gt;(hereafter fact compared to the composite &lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;act). The assertion of facts imputes a &lt;em&gt;truth&lt;/em&gt; value to facts and thus propositions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example - the fact is that there is a chessboard in my room which can be asserted via the proposition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is a chessboard in my room&lt;/em&gt; - T/F [atomic fact]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objects and thus names are devoid of any truth-value/meaning/sense on their own apart from denotation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example - &lt;em&gt;tree&lt;/em&gt; denotes the object but is meaningless in isolation in all aspects but its reference - &lt;em&gt;that is the meaning of a name is in the object it refers to&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how are these two modes of Reality(reality) consistent in the single manifold? It is through the relation between facts and objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facts are combinations of objects&lt;/strong&gt;[[3]]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what can we infer from the aforementioned axioms and definitions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atomic fact is the simplest possible fact. An object is not a fact. facts are combination of objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus there need to be at least two objects to constitute a fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest possible fact(the atomic fact) deals with the fact of existence only. That is the atomic fact only contains of existential propositions, and if not then it would be a composite i.e. a Fact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example - &lt;strong&gt;There (exists) is a chessboard(o_1) in my room(o_2)&lt;/strong&gt; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$\exists f = o_{1}o_{2} - True/False$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the set of all objects gives me the set of all possible facts and thus the set of all possible Facts. That is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$$o_i\in O\implies \Phi =(o_{i}o_{j}o_{k}\cdots): i\neq j\neq k\cdots &amp;amp; F\in \Phi$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The set of all possible Facts determines the actual state of affairs in the world. That is facts determine the state of affairs - whether something is the case or not the case(The case is the existence of the fact that is a fact = T).Therefore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All that is the case forms the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facts in logical space(possible facts from given objects) &lt;em&gt;constitute&lt;/em&gt; the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reality is the union of existence and non-existence of atomic facts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$$R \equiv \cup([f:f=T].[f&#39;:f=F)$$ or $$\cup(f.f&#39;)$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a preliminary, I will conclude the first part here. In the next part we will delve into the structure of language - syntax and semantics to analyze how we cognize relations in Reality projected from relations in reality/language and what it tells about us and the world. Thus we move into the realm of language first to capture Reality unlike this part where we mirrored a language from the realm of Reality - facts and objects. That is our main unit of analysis would now be &lt;em&gt;Propositions&lt;/em&gt; from which we shall derive relations between&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;propositions and thoughts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;propositions and images/pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;signs and symbols in language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natural language(empirical language) vs Logical language(language as a model of world)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to be mentioned that the first and last propositions are also the most quotable and quoted propositions of the entire work - and that is no coincidence. [↩︎]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in philosophical circles known as &lt;em&gt;Cartesian Dualism&lt;/em&gt; between mind and matter i.e. Subject and Object - The core structure of our natural languages. [↩︎]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it like this - facts are &lt;em&gt;relativistic&lt;/em&gt; - a black ink mark on its own is an abstraction unless it is in a canvas/floor/paper. Due to our use of natural language, we forget that fact are always contextual and embedded in relation to something - &lt;em&gt;I exist&lt;/em&gt; here it is understood that we have omitted the second object which is present in the form &lt;em&gt;I exist(in the world)&lt;/em&gt; . Interestingly that is why it will be senseless to say &lt;em&gt;This song is beautiful&lt;/em&gt; - because though there are two objects apparently, a particular song and the class of beautiful songs - the former is an object of substance, while the latter is not an object, unless it is the name of the song - &lt;em&gt;beautiful by abc&lt;/em&gt;  [↩︎]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiencing Time: Some excerpts from Thomas Mann’s - The Magic Mountain</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/posts-experiencing-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 15:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/posts-experiencing-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living in the times of a pandemic is no longer a phase we have to simply wait over, rather, as we become accustomed to the circumstances prevailing, we’re now moving towards an &lt;em&gt;equilibrium&lt;/em&gt; where such living becomes embedded in our psyche permanently, and consequently, becomes a permanent way of life.(Though surely, we are still in the infant stages of such a maturation and the future is ever uncertain)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these state of affairs, an experiment of nature on us one might conceive, we can approach this discontinuity as a tool for a more abstract unity, of what remains unchanged in our mode of living, which are in the domain of philosophical speculation. Indeed, these events make philosophical abstraction easier with empirical validity, and the philosophical concept of interest, of which there has been a definite empirical discontinuity, but at the same time within the chain of the broader philosophical continuity is the &lt;strong&gt;Concept of experiencing time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most of us, the initial stages of &lt;em&gt;pandemic living&lt;/em&gt; threw me off-balance, and in response I sought some refuge in escapist fictional literature; particularly &lt;em&gt;Thomas Mann’s - The Magic Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, which had been glaring at me from the bookshelf for two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I deem even a brief plot summary to be irrelevant in the scope of this essay, for what I am to discuss deals with a few excerpts from the book discussing the notion of &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Duration&lt;/em&gt;, which provoked my fascination in both applying  the Philosophy of &lt;em&gt;Henri Bergson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; and being relevant to the state of affairs we have found ourselves in.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3---mental-gymnastic&#34;&gt;Section 3 - Mental Gymnastic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protagonist’s temperature is being taken, taking around seven minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A:- ’Seven minutes! But they must be up!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B:- ‘Yes, but when you watch it, the time, it goes very slowly. I quite like the measuring, four times a day; for then you know what a minute - or seven of them- actually amounts to, up here in this place, where the seven days of the week whisk by the way they do!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A:- ‘You say “&lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt;”, but time isn’t actual. When it seems long to you, then it is long; when it seems short, why, then it is short. But how long or how short it actually is, that nobody knows.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B: - ‘How so? - we do measure it. We have watches and calendars for this purpose; and when a month is up, why, then up it is, for you and for me, and for all of us.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A:- ‘A minute is then as long as it seems to you when you measure yourself?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B:- ‘A minute is as long- it lasts as long- as it takes the second hand of my watch to complete a circuit.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A:- ‘But it takes a varied length of time for our senses. It is motion, isn’t it, motion in space? We measure time by space. How is that better than measuring space by time? Hamburg to Davos is twenty hours - that is, by train. On foot, how long is it? And in the mind, how long? Not a second. What is time? Space we perceive with our organs, senses of sight and touch.Good.  But where is the organ of time? How can we measure something about which we know nothing. We say that ‘Time passes’. Sure, let it pass. But how does one measure that? We believe time flows evenly, with scientific precision, but does it? As far as our consciousness is considered, it does not - We only assume it does, for the sake of convenience; and our units of measurement are purely arbitrary, sheer conventions…’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A much more nuanced take is taken up a few chapter later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-4---_excursus-on-the-sense-of-time_pp100&#34;&gt;Section 4 - &lt;em&gt;Excursus on the Sense of Time&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;strong&gt;pp:100&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is after all , something peculiar about the process of habituating oneself in a new place, the often laborious fitting in and getting used to, which one undertakes for its own sake, and of set purpose to break it all off as soon as it is complete, or not long thereafter, and to return to one’s former state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is an interval, an interlude, inserted with the object of recreation, into the tenor of life’s main concerns; its purpose the relief of the organism, which is perpetually busy at its task of self-renewal, and which was in danger, almost in process, of being vitiated, slowed down, relaxed, by the bald, unjointed monotony of its daily course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what then is the cause of this relaxation, this slowing down that takes place when one does the same thing for too long at a time? It is not so much physical or mental fatigue or exhaustion, for if that were the case then complete rest would be the best restorative. It is rather something psychical; It means that the perception of time tends, through periods of unbroken uniformity, to fall away; the perception of time, so closely bound up with the consciousness of life that one may not be weakened without the other suffering a sensible impairment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many false conceptions are held concerning the nature of tedium. In general, it is thought that the interestingness and novelty of the time-content are what ‘make the time pass’; that is to say, shorten it; whereas monotony and emptiness check and restrain its flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only true with reservations. Vacuity, monotony, have, indeed the property of lingering out the moment and the hour and of making them tiresome. But they are capable of contracting and dissipating the larger, the very large time-units, to the point of reducing them to nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And conversely, a full and interesting content can put wings to the hour and the day; yet it will lend to the general passage of time a weightiness, a breadth and solidity which cause the eventful years to flow far more slowly than those poor, bare, empty ones over which the wind passes and they are gone. Thus what we call tedium is rather an abnormal shortening of time consequent upon monotony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great spaces of time passed in unbroken uniformity tend to shrink together in a way to make the heart stop beating for fear; when one day is like all the others, then they are all like one; complete uniformity would make the longest life seem short, and as though it had stolen away from us unawares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habituation is a falling asleep or fatiguing of the sense of time; which explains why young years pass slowly, while later life flings itself faster and faster upon its course. We are aware that the intercalation of periods of change and novelty is the only means by which we can refresh our sense of time, strengthen, retard, rejuvenate it, and therewith renew our perception of life itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the purpose of our changes of air and scene, of all our sojourns at cures and bathing resorts; it is the secret of the healing power of change and incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first days in a new place; time has a youthful, that is to say, a broad and a sweeping, flow, persisting for some six to eight days. Then, as one ‘gets used to the place’, a gradual shrinkage makes itself felt. He who clings or, better expressed, wishes to cling to life, will shudder to see how the days grow light and lighter, how they scurry by like dead leaves, until the last week, of some four, perhaps, is uncannily fugitive and fleet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the quickening of the sense of time will flow out beyond the interval and reassert itself after the return to ordinary existence: the first days at home after the holiday will be lived with broader flow, freshly and youthfully - but only the first few, for one adjusts oneself more quickly to the rule than to the exception; and if the sense of time be already weakened by age, or - and this is a low sign of vitality - it was never really well developed, one drowses quickly back into the old life, and after four-and-twenty hours it is as though one had never been away, and the journey had been but a watch in the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henri Bergson was a Nobel Prize winning philosopher who introduced radically new conceptions of Duration in particular. &lt;em&gt;Check out ‘The Creative Evolution’, his most enduring work&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason is that I am still not close to reaching the halfway mark of this brick of a book.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If Spring comes, can Autumn be far behind?</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/if-spring-comes-can-autumn-be-far-behind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 11:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/if-spring-comes-can-autumn-be-far-behind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anxiety- To party or not to party?</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/anxiety-to-party-or-not-to-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 21:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/anxiety-to-party-or-not-to-party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreams</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 08:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Excerpt from Friedrich Nietzsche&#39;s &#39;Thus Spake Zarathustra&#39;</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/an-excerpt-from-friedrich-nietzsches-thus-spake-zarathustra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 14:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/an-excerpt-from-friedrich-nietzsches-thus-spake-zarathustra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Suicide of God</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/the-suicide-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 20:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/the-suicide-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Natural Calamity</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/a-natural-calamity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 07:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/a-natural-calamity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Good, Evil and all that Jazz- A Case for Objective Morality by Immanuel Kant</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/of-good-evil-and-all-that-jazz-a-case-for-objective-morality-by-immanuel-kant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 16:48:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/of-good-evil-and-all-that-jazz-a-case-for-objective-morality-by-immanuel-kant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quixotic Research Proposal in Economic Theory</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/a-quixotic-research-proposal-in-economic-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 07:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/a-quixotic-research-proposal-in-economic-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confessions of an Audiophile</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/confessions-of-an-audiophile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 10:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/confessions-of-an-audiophile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Behavioral Revolution in Economics</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/the-behavioral-revolution-in-economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 10:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/the-behavioral-revolution-in-economics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language, Thoughts, Metaphors and Analogies...</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/language-thoughts-metaphors-and-analogies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 14:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/language-thoughts-metaphors-and-analogies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Kierkegaard, Anxiety, and Selfhood</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/of-kierkegaard-anxiety-and-selfhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 07:12:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/of-kierkegaard-anxiety-and-selfhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new epoch of Humanity.</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/a-new-epoch-of-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 11:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/a-new-epoch-of-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Economics imperial among the social sciences? A philosophical approach.</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/is-economics-imperial-among-the-social-sciences-a-philosophical-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 06:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/is-economics-imperial-among-the-social-sciences-a-philosophical-approach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Propaganda Works</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/how-propaganda-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 17:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/how-propaganda-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economics- The Ultimate Philosophy.</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/economics-the-ultimate-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 10:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/economics-the-ultimate-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One man’s trash is another man’s treasure.</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/one-mans-trash-is-another-mans-treasure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 14:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/one-mans-trash-is-another-mans-treasure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ambiguity of morality</title>
      <link>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/have-a-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 12:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kabirchugh.xyz/posts/have-a-cookie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
